JOSH SARNA

Pasadena, CA • joshsarna@g.ucla.edu • (262) 313-8767 github.com/joshsarna • joshsarna.github.io • linkedin.com/in/joshuasarna

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

As a web developer with a physical science background, I bring to coding an analytical mindset ideal for problem solving and efficiency. I enjoy creating algorithms and incorporating mathematical tools into things I create. In my experience, software development and math both transcend disciplinary categorization. There's nothing that can't be better understood through math, and there's nothing that can't be furthered and improved by JavaScript.

Skills: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, VueJS, Vuex, React, Redux, Angular.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Python, Django, PHP, Wordpress, Pressable, Visual Basic .NET, HTML/CSS, SQL, Postgres, MySQL, R, MATLAB, Wolfram Mathematica, APIs, OOP, TDD, Git, Agile, Heroku, and AWS

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

2018 - Present

- LawnNinja: Build a gig-booking app centered around lawn work, providing a platform through which
 residents can post jobs and providers can claim them, record their work, and invoice residents; this is
 built using PostgreSQL, Rails, React, and React Native and is an ongoing Agile project
- **Backyard Organic Farms**: Build a produce delivery subscription website, using Wordpress; this is an ongoing project
- Ed Sarna: Build a personal website for a writer, using PostgreSQL, Rails, and VueJS; this is an ongoing project

Actualize, Software Engineer & TA

2018 - Present

- **TAship:** Teach Vue.js lessons to a live online class; assist students in developing their programming skills by providing supplementary instructional material, troubleshooting applications, and asking follow-up questions on coding techniques; grade student assignments through Github code review
- Middle Maps: Built an app that allows a user to search locations in Middle Earth (setting of Lord of the Rings) and to find routes between locations; learned Vue2-Filters, jsGraphics, and Heroku and wrote an efficient shortest-route algorithm in Ruby; the backend of this app is built on Rails with a PostgreSQL database, and the front-end is built on VueJS
- **Bootcamp:** Completed the three-month intensive Actualize bootcamp and learned Ruby, Rails, Javascript, VueJS, HTML, and CSS; learned how to build front-end, back-end, and full-stack apps; gained the ability to learn new frameworks and technologies quickly

Creative Support, Supported Living Specialist

2015 - 2018

- Supported clients with intellectual and developmental disabilities in learning Java and Python
- Modernized company system by creating online spreadsheets for tracking hours to supplement outdated paper system until payroll tracking was transitioned to a fully computerized system

EDUCATION

University of California at Los Angeles, Bachelor of Science in Physical Chemistry

2017

- Received mathematics minor
- Used Mathematica to model analytical mechanics problems; MATLAB to model analytical chemistry problems; Used Spartan, CaGe, and Kintecus software applications to model chemical reactions and species